# **Simon Rose**

### **Software Engineer**

simon-rose.co.uk

Sheffield, UK



+447791863017

### **Profile**

I am an ambitious and driven Software Engineer, experienced in designing and developing a range of web applications from web-based games to enterprise-level systems. I have a PhD in Computer Science and 7 years of professional software development experience, across both industry and academia. I have strong interpersonal and teaching skills and exceptional ability in organisation, planning and time management.

### **Experience**

### **Associate Lecturer - Sheffield Hallam University**

Oct 2016 - Present

- Preparing and delivering teaching content on a number of undergraduate Computer Science and Software Engineering modules.
- Supervising MSc, BSc and BEng students on their final year projects.
- End Point Assessor for the Digital and Technology Solutions Specialist MSc course.
- Student voice 'outstanding' member of staff 2016-17 and 2019-20.

### **Computing Teacher - Mercia Secondary School**

Jan 2019 - July 2019

- Preparing and teaching content in-line with the computing national curriculum.

### **Founder - Simon Rose Software Development**

Feb 2013 - Present

- Design, development and deployment of full stack web applications, primarily in JavaScript using front-end frameworks (AngularJS, Vue.js and React) and Node.js Express back-ends with MongoDB.
- Client liason and project management.

### Full Stack Software Engineer - 3Squared

Sept 2013 - May 2016

- Developing bespoke web applications in C# using ASP.NET MVC and Web Forms.
- Using web technologies including HTML, JavaScript and CSS.
- Application deployment using IIS.
- Working in Agile teams.
- Version control using Git and Team Foundation Server.
- API design and implementation.
- Time estimations and risk reviews.

### Education

### PhD in Computer Science - Sheffield Hallam University

Oct 2016 - Sept 2019

Title: Developing Children's Computational Thinking Skills using Programming Games

Supervisors: Dr Jacob Habgood and Dr Tim Jay

Published work in academic journals and presented at several conferences during the PhD.

## MComp Software Engineering - Sheffield Hallam University First Class (Honours)

Sept 2011 - July 2016

Award Classification Mark: 86.55%

### **Skills**

Programming Languages	Frameworks/Software	Other Skills
<ul><li>- JavaScript (and TypeScript)</li></ul>	- Node.js	- Organised
- C#	- Angular	- Motivated
- C++	<ul><li>- Vue.js (and Vuex)</li></ul>	- Pragmatic
- Java	<ul> <li>React (and Redux)</li> </ul>	- Adaptable
- SQL	<ul> <li>Mocha/Chai/Jest/Cypress</li> </ul>	- Able to lead
- PHP	NET	- Business awareness
- HTML	- MongoDB	- Widely-read
- CSS (and LESS/SASS)	- Photoshop	<ul> <li>Teaching/presenting</li> </ul>
	- InDesign	

### **Projects**

### Cognitive Function Task

May 2020 - July 2020

- An application that allows researchers to flexibly develop and customise cognitive function task assessments.
- Split into three parts: a CMS for managing tasks, an progressive web application for running tasks and a REST API that handles data.
- Developed using Vue.js for the front-end and Node.js/Express for the back-end.
- Research project for the Centre of Mathematical Cognition at Loughborough University.

Pirate Plunder Sept 2017 - July 2018

- Educational block-based programming game.
- Teaches players how and why to use procedures the Scratch programming tool.
- MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack.
- Developed as part of my PhD.

Speakeasy Jan 2016 - May 2016

- Lead programmer in a team of 3.
- Augmentative and alternative communication (AAC) speech generation software designed for children with cerebral palsy.
- Uses semantic compaction to combine chosen words to form more complex sentences.
- MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack.

### **Interests**

### Sport

I enjoy playing and watching sport, primarily football and resistance work in the gym. I play 6-a-side football regularly.

### Reading

I like to read and am always striving to broaden my knowledge and understanding on a wide range of topics. I set myself the goal to read a book a week in 2016 and have continued to exceed this target each year.

### **Travel**

I am a keen traveller and enjoy backpacking. I have travelled around South East Asia, South America, Japan and several European countries in the last few years.

### References

Dr Jacob Habgood

Director of Education Partnerships Sumo Digital jhabgood@sumo-digital.com **Mr James Fox** 

Commercial Director 3Squared james.fox@3squared.com